Guide to the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Miscellaneous manuscripts collection
1425-2002
MS 352
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
57.27
(108 boxes)
An artificial collection of correspondence, writings, photographs, and other documents relating to assorted individuals, families, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
J. Walter and Evangeline Cunningham Bassett material (#478) gift of Paul Keane, 2013.
Existence and Location of Copies
Manuscript book of music written by Aaron Thompson is also available on microfilm (130 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM44.
Journals of Sir John Lefroy are available on microfilm (1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM42.
Correspondence (1833-1859) of Captain William Silver relating to the pepper and opium trade is also available on microfilm (142 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM186.
Central America - Mosquito Kingdom manuscript is also available on microfilm (139 frames on 1 reel, 35 mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM209.
Letterbook (1849-1850) of Matthew Calbraith Perry is also available on microfilm (1 reel, 35 mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM245.
Letterbook (1826-1858) of Peck and Phelps is also available on microfilm (93 frames on 1 reel, 35 mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM256.
Arrangement
Arranged in eighteen series: I. A-B. II. C-D. III. E-G. IV. H-J. V. K-L. VI. M. VII. N-O. VIII. P-R. IX. S. X. T. XI. U-V. XII. W. XIII. X-Z. XIV. Numerical, 1-100. XV. Numerical, 101-200. XVI. Numerical, 201-300. XVII. Numerical, 301-400. XVIII. Numerical, 401-500., and Oversized.
Scope and Contents
An artificial collection of correspondence, writings, photographs, and other documents relating to assorted individuals, families, and organizations.
- A-B, Series I
  - Abbott, William Cortez, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abercrombie, John Joseph, 1838, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abrantes, Miguel Calmon de pin e Almeida, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Achard, Louis Amadée Eugène, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Acheson, Edward Campion, 1908, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Achmet, Hammett, 1839-1842 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adam, Juliette (Lamber) La Messine, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adam, Paul Augusts Marie, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adams, Abijah, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adams, Andrew, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adams, Charles Francis, 1846, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adams, Daniel Lucius, 1833-1898 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adams, James Truslow, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adams, John Quincy (1767-1848), 1826-1827, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Adams, John Quincy (-1894), 1890 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Adams, William, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Adrien (French actor), 1847 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ahern, George P., 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Akabane, Shiro, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Akkeringa, I. E., 1860-1862 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Albany Congress, 1754 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Aldrich, James, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Alexander, Robert and Elabeth, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Algemeen Syndicaat van Suikerfabrikanten op Java, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Allen, John, 1828-1838 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Allen, Meigs, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Allen family, 1792-1868, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Alvord, Mary Eliza (Landon), 1836-1855, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ambler, Richard Charles, 1878-1889 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ambler, Richard Charles, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Bible Society, Yale College, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Education Society, Yale College, 1827-1833 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Geological Society, 1819-1826 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Anderson, Robbins Battell, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Andrews, John Bertram, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Andruss, William Irving, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Anson, George (Lord Anson), 1753 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Anstruther, Philip, 1779 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Anthony, Susan Brownell, 1882, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Armstrong, Thomas, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Armstrong, William, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Arnold, Benedict, 1774-1780, 1902, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Arnold, H. V., 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Arthur, Sarah B., 1867 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Aspern and Kaiserin Elisabeth (ships), 1904-1905 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Astef'ev, Nikolai Aleksandrovich, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Astor, John Jacob, 1812, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Atwater, Edward Elias, 1835-1861, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Atwater, Eldad, 1773 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Audubon, John James, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Augur, Horace, 1823-1832, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Augusta, Maine, South Parish Congregational Church, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Austin, Samuel, 1780 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Austin Memorial Collection, 1744-1837 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Babcock, Sidney, family, 1818-1885, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Babcock, William L., 1861-1865, undated (Box 4, Folder 57-58)
  - Bacon, Asahel and Charles, 1818-1821 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Bacon, Francis Henry, 1881-1936 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Bacon, George Blagden, 1855-1856 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Bacon, John Watson Collection, 1848-1863 (Box 4, Folder 62-63)
  - Bacon, Leonard, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Baddeley, Sir John James, 1879-1914 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Badger, Shreve Cowles Collection, 1777-1949 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Badger, William, 1890-1891 (Box 5, Folder 67-68)
  - Bainton, Roland Herbert, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Baldwin, Abraham, 1780-1819 (Box 5, Folder 71-72)
  - Baldwin, Charles H., undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Baldwin, Henry, 1866, undated (Box 5, Folder 74-75)
  - Baldwin, Theron, 1824-1868 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Ballou, Franklin, 1898-1918 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Balsan, Consuelo (Vanderbilt), undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Bancroft, George, 1864-1883 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Banister, Zilpah Polly, 1823 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Banks, Charles Edward, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Bannan, Thomas Ridgway, 1847 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Barber, Noyes, 1831-1832 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Barber family, 1847-1887 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Barbour, James Richard Jr., 1861-1863 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Barnes, William, 1844-1906 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Barney, Hiram, 1878-1879 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Barnsley, Godfrey, 1825 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1843-1885 (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Barrett, Oliver Roger, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Barrière-Flavy, Casimir, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Barotow, Lydia, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Bartholomew Family Papers, 1813-1914 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Bartlett, Henry, 1795 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Bassett, Ebenezer Don Carlos, 1874 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Bassett, G. W., 1853 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Batavia, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Bates, Henry Stratton, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Baxter Collection, 1800-1938 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Bayard, James Ashton, 1856 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Bayard, Thomas F., 1885-1888 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Bayne Family Papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Beach, David N., 1871 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Beardslee, Raymond A., 1864-1916 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Beardsley, Mary E., 1877 (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Becke, Louis, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Beckman, Gerard G., 1765 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Belcher, Nathan, 1855-1858 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Belmont, August, 1853 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Benét, William Rose, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Benites, Gregorio, undated (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - Benjamin, Judah Phillip, 1861-1929 (Box 7, Folder 112)
  - Bennett, James Gordon, 1827-1866 (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Bennett, James O'Donnell, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Bergschneider, Georg, 1929-1936 (Box 8, Folder 115-116)
  - Bergson, Henri Louis, 1911-1938 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Berlespsch, Hans Herman Carl Ludvig, graf von, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Bernard, Sir Francis, undated (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Berrien, John MacPherson, 1827 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Bertram, Mathias, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Betts, Frederick Joel, 1848-1861 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Bibbins, Israel, 1830-1863 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Biddle, Clement, 1807 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Binney, Horace, 1853 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Birdseye Family genealogy, undated (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Bishop, Herbert Morton, 1906-1912 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Bishop, Nathaniel, 1798, 1815 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Bjerregard, Carl H. A., 1903 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Blackwell, Antoinette Louisa (Brown), 1877 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Blaine, James Gillespie, 1863-1891 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Blair, Francis Preston, 1831 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Blair, Montgomery, 1862 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Blaney Family Papers, 1775-1825 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Bloch, Ernest, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Blount, William, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Boardman, Benjamin, 1756-1757, 1790 (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - Bohannan, Ambrose, 1762 (Box 9, Folder 138)
  - Bolton, Dorothea, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 139)
  - Boon, William C., 1837 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - Boone Family, 1780-1792 (Box 9, Folder 141)
  - Borchert, Charles, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Bostwick, Elisha, 1776 (Box 9, Folder 143)
  - Bosworth, Daniel, 1823 (Box 9, Folder 144)
  - Botsford, Amos, 1776-1784 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Botsford, David, 1818-1821 (Box 9, Folder 146)
  - Botta, Anne Charlotte, undated (Box 9, Folder 147)
  - Boucicault, Dion, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - Bourienne, Louis Antoine Fauvelet de, undated (Box 9, Folder 149)
  - Boutier, N. Y., 1802-1805 (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - Boveri, Theodor, undated (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - Bowen, Clarence Winthrop, 1881 (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - Bowman, John Elliot, 1827 (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - Bowman, Virginia, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - Boyd, John, 1829 (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - Brace, Charles Loring, undated (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - Braden, Spruille, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - Bradley, Omar Nelson, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - Brainard, Morgan B., 1912-1927 (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - Breck, Samuel, 1797 (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Breckenridge-Wetber Collection, 1739-1757 (Box 9, Folder 161)
  - Bremer, Frederika, undated (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Brewer, James Norris, 1815-1827 (Box 9, Folder 163)
  - Brewster, William, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 164)
  - Brigham, John Clark, 1841-1856 (Box 10, Folder 165)
  - Bright, John, 1864 (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 167)
  - Brinton, Howard F., undated (Box 10, Folder 168-169)
  - Britten, Harriet G., undated (Box 10, Folder 170)
  - Brockway, John Hall, 1818 (Box 10, Folder 171)
  - Brookhaven, N.Y. Committee of Safety, 1775-1776 (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - Brooks, Phillips, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Brown, Horace Spalding, 1753-1943 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Brown, Olympia, undated (Box 10, Folder 175)
  - Brown, Samuel, 1767 (Box 10, Folder 176)
  - Brown, William Moseley, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 177)
  - Browne, John, 1779 (Box 10, Folder 178)
  - Brownell, Gertrude, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 179)
  - Brunhouse, Robert L., 1933 (Box 10, Folder 180)
  - Bryant, William Cullen, 1837 (Box 10, Folder 181)
  - Bryant Family Collection, undated (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - Buchanan, James, undated (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Buckingham, William A., 1864 (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - Buddhist Texts, 1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 185)
  - Buell, John H., 1800 (Box 10, Folder 186)
  - Buell, Samuel, 1739 (Box 10, Folder 187)
  - Bulkeley, William E., 1826 (Box 10, Folder 188)
  - Bullock, Oliver, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 189)
  - Bulow, Bernhard Ernst von, 1879 (Box 10, Folder 190)
  - Bumstead, Henry Andrews Collection, undated (Box 11, Folder 191-193)
  - Bunnell, Joseph, undated (Box 11, Folder 194)
  - Bunsen, Christian Karl Josias, undated (Box 11, Folder 195)
  - Buonistalli, Antonio., undated (Box 11, Folder 196)
  - Burbeck, John Jr., 1814 (Box 11, Folder 197)
  - Burch, John Chilton, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 198)
  - Burd, Edward, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 199)
  - Burga Larrea, Carlos, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 200)
  - Burnet, John, undated (Box 11, Folder 201)
  - Burnham Family, 1798-1880 (Box 11, Folder 202)
  - Burton, Cecelia, 1860 (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - Burton, J., 1915 (Box 11, Folder 204)
  - Bushnell, Samuel K., 1915-1918 (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - Byrd, Richard Evelyn, undated (Box 11, Folder 206)
- C - D, Series II
  - Cadwalader, George, 1848 (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell, 1816-1831 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Cameron, Simon, 1865 (Box 12, Folder 209)
  - Camp, Hiram, 1893 (Box 12, Folder 210)
  - Campbell, Cassandana (Miller), 1838 (Box 12, Folder 211)
  - Campbell, Helen (Stuart), 1891 (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Canale, George D., 1858 (Box 12, Folder 213)
  - Cannon, Joseph Gurney, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - Cardoza, J. B. N., 1933 (Box 12, Folder 215)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin Nathan, undated (Box 12, Folder 216-217)
  - Carey, Lea and Co., 1837 (Box 12, Folder 218)
  - Carey, Lewis James, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 219)
  - Carlisle, James Mandeville, 1843, 1862, 1877 (Box 12, Folder 220)
  - Carlisle, Mary Jane (Goodson), 1896 (Box 12, Folder 221)
  - Carll, Albert G., 1856-1857 (Box 12, Folder 222)
  - Carpenter, Charles Everly, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 223)
  - Carpenter, Gerard, 1837-1849 (Box 12, Folder 224)
  - Carter, James Coolidge, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 225)
  - Carting Island Seine, 1819-1829 (Box 12, Folder 226)
  - Cashin, Herschel V., 1899 (Box 12, Folder 227)
  - Cass, Lewis, 1833-1834 (Box 12, Folder 228)
  - Cassirer, Toni (Bondy), 1951 (Box 12, Folder 229)
  - Catholic Mission to China, 1705-1726 (Box 12, Folder 230)
  - Catlin, George, 1862 (Box 12, Folder 231)
  - Catlin, Nicholas William, 1857-1867 (Box 12, Folder 232)
  - Causten, James H., 1858 (Box 13, Folder 233)
  - Caxton, William, undated (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - Central America, 1820-1847, undated (Box 13, Folder 235-239)
  - Chabot, Alphonse Marie, undated (Box 13, Folder 240)
  - Chamberlain, Abiram, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 241)
  - Chamberlain, Robert Rensselaer, undated (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - Chambers, John, 1832 (Box 13, Folder 243)
  - Champion, Epaphroditus, 1816 (Box 13, Folder 244)
  - Champion, Reuben, undated (Box 13, Folder 245)
  - Champion Family, 1830-1832 (Box 13, Folder 246)
  - Chandler, Charles Frederick, undated (Box 13, Folder 247)
  - Chapman, Edward Mortimer, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 248)
  - Chapman, John Grant, 1831 (Box 13, Folder 249)
  - Chapman, Samuel, 1788 (Box 13, Folder 250)
  - Chapman, Susanna Pearson (Alexandra), 1841 (Box 13, Folder 251)
  - Chaptal de Chanteloup, Jean Antoine, Comte, undated (Box 13, Folder 252)
  - Charvet, M. J. G., undated (Box 13, Folder 253)
  - Chase, John, 1853 (Box 13, Folder 254)
  - Chautautiua Institution, N.Y., 1934-1936 (Box 13, Folder 255)
  - Cheney, Clifford Dudley, undated (Box 14, Folder 256)
  - Chéradame, André, 1941-1945 (Box 14, Folder 257)
  - Cherót, Henri, 1898-1899 (Box 14, Folder 258)
  - Chew, Benjamin, 1768 (Box 14, Folder 259)
  - Chickering Institute, Cincinnati, undated (Box 14, Folder 260)
  - Child, Calvin Goddard, 1859-1862 (Box 14, Folder 261)
  - Chinese Laundry Bill, 1853 (Box 14, Folder 262)
  - Chittenden, John D., 1857 (Box 14, Folder 263)
  - Choate, Rufus, 1840, 1848 (Box 14, Folder 264)
  - Churchill, William, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 265)
  - Cicognani, Francesco Leopoldo, Conte, 1835 (Box 14, Folder 266)
  - Clarendon, George William Frederick Villiers, 1850 (Box 14, Folder 267)
  - Clarges, Sir Thomas, 1685 (Box 14, Folder 268)
  - Clark, Mary Ann, 1834-1836 (Box 14, Folder 269)
  - Clarke, Thomas, 1677 (Box 14, Folder 270)
  - Clay, Henry, 1824-1851 (Box 14, Folder 271)
  - Clay, John Randolph, 1852 (Box 14, Folder 272)
  - Cleugh, Sophia, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 273)
  - Cleveland, Francis Folsom, 1886, 1889, undated (Box 14, Folder 274)
  - Cleveland, Grover, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 275)
  - Cleveland, James Bradford, 1850 (Box 14, Folder 276)
  - Cleveland, Richard Jeffry, 1849 (Box 14, Folder 277)
  - Cleveland, Rose Elizabeth, 1889 (Box 14, Folder 278)
  - Clifton, Joel B., 1834 (Box 14, Folder 279)
  - Clinton, Cornelia Tappan, undated (Box 14, Folder 280)
  - Clinton, Sir Henry, 1781, 1803, undated (Box 14, Folder 281)
  - Cloete, Stuart, undated (Box 14, Folder 282)
  - Coal and Oil Surveys in Kentucky and Utah, 1901-1914, undated (Box 14, Folder 283-284)
  - Cobden, Richard, 1851-1865 (Box 14, Folder 285)
  - Cochran, John, undated (Box 14, Folder 286)
  - Coffin, Thomas Aston, 1853, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 287)
  - Coit, William, 1782-1785 (Box 15, Folder 288)
  - Colfax, Ellen W. (Wade), 1886 (Box 15, Folder 289)
  - Colt, Peter, 1792-1793 (Box 15, Folder 290)
  - Colwell, Howard, Collection, 1815-1881 (Box 15, Folder 291)
  - Comfort, George Fisk, 1899 (Box 15, Folder 292)
  - Commonplace Books, 1789-1806, undated (Box 15, Folder 293)
  - Comstock, William G., 1835 (Box 15, Folder 294)
  - Congregational Church Collection, [1781?]-1912 (Box 16, Folder 295-296)
  - Conkling, Clinton Levering, 1860-1864 (Box 16, Folder 297)
  - Conkling, Roscoe, 1868 (Box 16, Folder 298)
  - Cook, Albert Stanburrough, 1892, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 299)
  - Cooke, Mordecai Cubitt, 1851 (Box 16, Folder 300)
  - Coblidge, Calvin, 1912-1931, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 301)
  - Cooper, James Earnest Collection, 1757-1861 (Box 16, Folder 302)
  - Copping, Mrs., undated (Box 17, Folder 303)
  - Corbett, Boston, 1865 (Box 17, Folder 304)
  - Corbin, Arthur Linton, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 305)
  - Cosgrove, Henry Buckalew, 1894-1933, undated (Box 17, Folder 306)
  - Court, William, 1815 (Box 17, Folder 307)
  - Cox, Samuel Hanson, 1830 (Box 17, Folder 308)
  - Coxey, Willard Douglas, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 309)
  - Crabtree, Lotta M., undated (Box 17, Folder 310)
  - Crane, Abraham, undated (Box 17, Folder 311)
  - Croaker, J. B., 1874 (Box 17, Folder 312)
  - Cromwell, Oliver, 1651 (Box 17, Folder 313)
  - Croly, Jane (Cunningham), 1890 (Box 17, Folder 314)
  - Cruikshanks, John, 1813 (Box 17, Folder 315)
  - Culin, Stewart, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 316)
  - Cunmings, Joseph, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 317)
  - Cummins, Jonathan, 1887 (Box 17, Folder 318)
  - Cunningham, Robert P., undated (Box 17, Folder 319)
  - Cunningham, William, 1759 (Box 17, Folder 320)
  - Currier, A. O., 1863 (Box 17, Folder 321)
  - Curtis, Edward, 1836-1840 (Box 17, Folder 322)
  - Curtis, George William, 1872 (Box 17, Folder 323)
  - Cushing, Caleb, 1876 (Box 17, Folder 324)
  - Cushing, John, 1709 (Box 17, Folder 325)
  - Cushman, Charlotte Saunders, 1858, 1869, undated (Box 17, Folder 326)
  - Cushman, Joshua, 1820 (Box 17, Folder 327)
  - Custis, George Washington Parke, 1854 (Box 17, Folder 328)
  - Cutler, Manasseh, 1790 (Box 17, Folder 329)
  - Daggett, David L., 1838-1839, 1852-1864 (Box 17, Folder 330)
  - Dallas, George Miflin, 1835 (Box 17, Folder 331)
  - Dal Monte, P. G., undated (Box 17, Folder 332)
  - Danforth, James Romeyn, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 333)
  - Daniels, George P., 1840 (Box 18, Folder 334)
  - Daniels, Lyman I., 1833-1838 (Box 18, Folder 335)
  - Darby, Aaron Family, 1822-1899, undated (Box 18, Folder 336)
  - Darling, Joseph Family, 1795, 1805-1848 (Box 18, Folder 337)
  - Davenport, Addington, undated (Box 18, Folder 338)
  - Davenport, Edmund Sharington, 1930, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 339)
  - Davenport, William, 1838 (Box 18, Folder 340)
  - Davenport, William Family, 1837-1852 (Box 18, Folder 341)
  - Davenport Family, [1802?]-1847, undated (Box 18, Folder 342-344)
  - Davio, Manuel, undated (Box 18, Folder 345)
  - Davis, John G., 1831 (Box 18, Folder 346)
  - Davis, Samuel P., 1832 (Box 18, Folder 347)
  - Davis, Simon Jr., 1816 (Box 18, Folder 348)
  - Davison, Alexander M., 1836, 1851 (Box 18, Folder 349)
  - Day, Donald, 1942-1943 (Box 18, Folder 350)
  - Dean, Gilbert, 1833-1841, undated (Box 18, Folder 351)
  - Dean, Joseph, 1836 (Box 19, Folder 352)
  - Dean, William, 1841 (Box 19, Folder 353)
  - Deering, John, 1826-1832 (Box 19, Folder 354)
  - Degrand, Peter Paul Francis, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 355)
  - Delaporte, Louis Joseph, 1910 (Box 19, Folder 356)
  - Delavan, David Bryson, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 357)
  - Delaware and Hudson Canal Company, 1829-1837, 1861-1874, undated (Box 19, Folder 358)
  - Deming, William, 1804 (Box 19, Folder 359)
  - Denison, Charles, 1827-1831 (Box 19, Folder 360)
  - Denslow, William Wallace, undated (Box 19, Folder 361)
  - Derby, Joseph, 1897-1945 (Box 19, Folder 362)
  - Dering, Sir Edward, 1673 (Box 19, Folder 363)
  - D'Ewes, Sir Symonds, undated (Box 19, Folder 364)
  - Dewey, George: Dewey Home Fund, 1899 (Box 19, Folder 365)
  - Dewey, Israel, 1849 (Box 19, Folder 366)
  - DeWitt, Thomas, undated (Box 19, Folder 367)
  - Dickinson, Austin, 1844 (Box 19, Folder 368)
  - Dickinson, Baxter, 1813-1817, 1853 (Box 19, Folder 369)
  - Dilworth, Hiram Powers, undated (Box 19, Folder 370)
  - Dimancescu, Dimitri Dem, 1925-1948, undated (Box 19, Folder 371)
  - Dingley, Frank P., 1894 (Box 19, Folder 372)
  - Dix, Dorothea Lynde, 1855 (Box 19, Folder 373)
  - Dixon, James, 1855, 1862 (Box 19, Folder 374)
  - Doddridge, Mrs. Perry, 1876 (Box 19, Folder 375)
  - Dolley, William, 1860 (Box 19, Folder 376)
  - Doty, Alvin, 1807 (Box 19, Folder 377)
  - Downing, Sir George, and Edward Whalley, 1653 (Box 19, Folder 378)
  - Drake, Samuel Gardiner, 1845 (Box 19, Folder 379)
  - Dreier Family, 1833-1852, undated (Box 20, Folder 380)
  - Dresser, H., 1828, 1831 (Box 20, Folder 381)
  - Duck, James Nixon, 1821-1848 (Box 20, Folder 382)
  - Dudley, Charles Edward, 1822 (Box 20, Folder 383)
  - Dudley, Joseph, 1704-1710 (Box 20, Folder 384)
  - Dudley, Rev. Samuel, 1664 (Box 20, Folder 385)
  - Duer, William, 1700 (Box 20, Folder 386)
  - Dunbar, Elizabeth, 1938-1940 (Box 20, Folder 387)
  - Dupauloup, Felix Antoine Philibert, é-vêque d'Orleans, undated (Box 20, Folder 388)
  - Durkee, Charles, 1858-1860 (Box 20, Folder 389)
  - Dutton, Gov. Henry, 1832-1856 (Box 20, Folder 390)
  - Dwight, Theodore Frelinghuysen, [1898?] (Box 20, Folder 391)
  - Dyer, Elisha, 1858 (Box 20, Folder 392)
- E - G, Series III
  - Earl, Catherine, 1846 (Box 21, Folder 393)
  - Earle, Alice Morse, 1895 (Box 21, Folder 394)
  - Eastman, Arthur McArthur, 1864 (Box 21, Folder 395)
  - Eaton, William Wallace, 1875-1880, undated (Box 21, Folder 396)
  - Eberhard, Alfred, 1808 (Box 21, Folder 397)
  - Edison, Thomas Alva, 1912, 1921, undated (Box 21, Folder 398-399)
  - Edmonds, William, 1902-1906 (Box 21, Folder 400)
  - Edson, Charles Leroy, undated (Box 21, Folder 401)
  - Edwards, Charles Lincoln, 1896 (Box 21, Folder 402)
  - Eggleston, Edward Porter, 1900-1914 (Box 21, Folder 403)
  - Ehrmann, Sara R., 1958 (Box 21, Folder 404)
  - Eichelberger, Martin Smyser, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 405)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1929-1947 (Box 21, Folder 406)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David, 1948-1956 (Box 21, Folder 407)
  - Elam, Samuel, 1798 (Box 22, Folder 408)
  - Elderkin, Joshua, 1779 (Box 22, Folder 409)
  - Eldred, Calvin P., 1933 (Box 22, Folder 410)
  - Eldridge, James Stuart, 1863-1868 (Box 22, Folder 411)
  - Ellet, Elizabeth Fries (Lummis), undated (Box 22, Folder 412)
  - Ellis, Richard, 1927 (Box 22, Folder 413)
  - Ellmaker, Amos, 1828 (Box 22, Folder 414)
  - Ellsworth, Oliver, 1787, 1928, undated (Box 22, Folder 415)
  - Ellsworth, William Wolcott, 1829-1830 (Box 22, Folder 416)
  - Emerson, Caleb, 1818 (Box 22, Folder 417)
  - Emerson, Sarah D., 1839 (Box 22, Folder 418)
  - Ennis, John F., 1853 (Box 22, Folder 419)
  - Enos, Roger, 1793 (Box 22, Folder 420)